A last report in the group of site content reports is the exit report.
أخر تقرير في مجموعة تقارير محتوى الموقع هو تقرير نسبة الخروج.
I said before that I don't think this is the most helpful report you can find here,
قلت سابقاً أني لا أعتقد أنه أفيد تقرير يمكنك إيجاده هنا،
but now that we have talked about bounces a lot,
ولكن بما أننا تحدثنا عن معدلات الخروج من الصفحة بكثرة،
I want to pause and make sure we get a difference between an exit and a bounce.
أريد التوقف والتأكد من أننا نفهم الفرق بين نسبة الخروج ومعدل الخروج من الصفحة.
Remember how we said that a bounce is a visit where
أتذكرون عندما قلنا أن معدل الخروج من الصفحة هو زيارة حيث
the person left your site from the entrance page.
يخرج الشخص من موقعك من صفحة المدخل؟
Basically, they enter your site and immediately leave.
بشكل أساسي، يدخلون موقعك ويخرجون مباشرة.
A page is bounce rate does refers to the percentage of
معدل الخروج من الصفحة يشير إلى نسبة
visits where this page is the only page in the session.
الزيارات التي تكون هذه الصفحة هي الوحيدة في فترة قضاء المستخدم على الموقع.
An exit is different,
لكن نسبة الخروج مختلفة،
it means the user exits from this page
تعني أن المستخدم يخرج من هذه الصفحة
regardless of how many pages the user visited in that session.
بغض النظر عن عدد الصفحات التي زارها المستخدم في فترة قضائه على الموقع.
So a bounce would be considered an exit but not every exit is a bounce.
إذن سيعتبر معدل الخروج كنسبة خروج ولكن ليست كل نسبة خروج هي معدل خروج.
When we study pages,
عند تفحصنا للصفحات،
we talk about the bounce suite and the percent exits,
نتحدث عن باقة معدل الخروج ونسبة الخروج من الصفحة،
and here is a refresher on the definitions.
وهنا تذكير للتعريفات.
The bounce rate is the percentage of single page visits,
معدل الخروج من الصفحة هو نسبة الزيارات للصفحة الواحدة،
so visits in which the person left your site
أي الزيارات التي خرج فيها الشخص من موقعك
from the entrance page without interacting with the page.
بعد صفحة المدخل من دون التفاعل معها.
Percent exits is the number of exits
نسبة الخروج هي عدد مرات الخروج
divided by the number of page views for the page or a set of pages.
مقسومة على عدد مشاهدات الصفحة أو مجموعة صفحات.
It indicates how often users exit from
وهي تشير إلى عدد مرات خروج المستخدمين من
that page or set of pages when they view the pages.
الصفحة أو مجموعة الصفحات بعد مشاهدتهم لها.
Now just so we're all clear on the difference,
ولنكون واضحين في الاختلاف،
let's take another look at an example,
لنلقي نظرة أخرى على مثال،
this time for Bamboo HR.
وهذا المرة ستكون لـBamboo HR
First, let's look at what a bounce looks like.
أولاً، لنرى ما يبدو عليه معدل الخروج من الصفحة.
For the sake of this example,
في سبيل المثال،
we choose the pricing page as the landing page.
نختار صفحة التسعير كصفحة هبوط.
And because the visitor left immediately after landing on
ولأن الزائر خرج مباشرة بعد هبوطه
this page without any other interaction on the page,
على الصفحة من دون أي تفاعل أخر عليها،
for instance, clicking on a link,
كالنقر على رابط مثلاً،
discounts towards the bounce rate for the pricing page.
خصومات من معدل الخروج لصفحة التسعير.
And since the visitors came to my site and left,
وبما أن الزوار جاءوا إلى موقعي ورحلوا،
it also counts towards the exit rate for this pricing page.
فستحسب أيضاً كنسبة خروج لصفحة التسعير هذه.
Now let's take a look at an exit that's not a bounce.
لننظر الآن إلى نسبة خروج ليست معدل خروج.
In this case, the landing page is the home page and the visitor goes
في هذه الحالة تكون صفحة الهبوط هي الصفحة الرئيسية، ويذهب الزائر
beyond this page interacting with it by clicking on the pricing link.
ما بعد هذه الصفحة متفاعلاً معها عن طريق النقر على رابط التسعير.
The visitor that lands on the pricing page and decides to exit by typing in another URL.
الزائر الذي يدخل صفحة التسعير ويقرر الخروج عن طريق طباعة رابط موقع أخر.
So discounts towards an exit for the pricing page,
إذن خصومات كنسبة خروج لصفحة التسعير،
but this is not a bounce since there was more than one page in the session.
لكنه ليس معدل خروج بما أنه كان هنالك أكثر من صفحة خلال فترة القضاء على الموقع.
As I said before,
كما قلت سابقاً،
users need to exit at some point,
على المستخدمين الخروج عند نقطة ما،
it's normal and those exits are going to be distributed across your site.
إنه أمر طبيعي، وستتوزع نسب الخروج عبر موقعك.
However, if you see disproportional exits on pages that are part of
ولكن إذا رأيت نسب خروج غير متكافئة على الصفحات التي هي جزء
a conversion or check-out path or that represents a clear beginning of an action,
من تحول أو دفع أو ما تمثل بداية واضحة لفعل.
then you may want to take a closer look.
فعندها قد تريد إلقاء نظرة فاحصة أكثر.
In the example we just walked through,
في المثال الذي عرضناه للتو،
if many people are exiting from this pricing page,
إذا قام العديد من الناس بالخروج من صفحة التسعير هذه،
Bamboo HR may find that it is not achieving its goals with
فقد تجد شركة BambooHR أنها لا تحقق أهدافها
this page as it is clearly meant to get users to submit information.
مع هذه الصفحة التي كان هدفها بشكل واضح جعل المستخدمين تقديم معلوماتهم.
In that case, they may want to test
وفي تلك الحال، قد يريدون تجربة
different versions of this page and see whether they would do better.
نسخاً مختلفة لهذه الصفحة ورؤية ما إذا كانت ستكون أفضل.